Finding Aid for the Livingston Gearhart Collection of Scores, 1930-1996
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Compilations and sketchbooks, 1935-2004, III; Folder 229-427
  - Gearhart, Livingston Collection 1945 [between 1945 and 1976], 1 ms. sketchbook ([64] p.); 32 cm.; Arrangements for multiple types of ensembles. Title from prefatory page. "I find that most of this stuff has served multi-purpose, much of it used in print--largely in Sessions bks."--Note from Livingston Gearhart on inside cover. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 13, Folder 237)
    Contents: Round / Purcell -- Theme from Brandenburg no. 2 / J.S. Bach -- Lift thine eyes: from Elijah / Mendelssohn -- The people's joy and happy dances: from Biblical sonata / Kuhnau -- Rounds / Caldara -- Canon a 7 / J.S. Bach -- Canon 4 in 2 / Sweelinck -- "Follow the leader" / Dr. Hayes -- Composition regeln / Sweelinck -- [Untitled piece] / "in Sweelinck: Autheur Willaert" -- Dance of the ballerina from Petrouchka / [Stravinsky] -- Canon à 8 / Tallis -- Chromatic study or Strange interlude or Frankenstein's Revenge / L.G. -- Blessed morpheus: from Joede / Brahms -- Warning / C. M. v. Weber -- Lacrimosa / Schubert -- Gebt mir zu trinken / Schumann -- [Untitled piece] -- Russian dance / Tschaikovsky-Glinka -- Nocturne / Mendelssohn -- Meistersinger chorale -- Prelude (Close quarters) -- "Lady Nelson's" reel -- Welsh morris dance -- Gigue; Tenoes; Minuet / from English Duos -- Presto / Old English -- Fanfare / Old English -- Canon / Gottfried Finger -- Sky blue -- [Silent night -- Good King Wenceslas] -- [Hark the herald angels sing] "Revised for trumpets" -- Round / L.G. Sept. 20 -- Bugle woogie I / Round -- Bugle woogie II -- We, three kings -- God rest ye -- Noel -- Adeste -- Jingle bells -- Christ the Lord -- Bell-tone breakdown -- [Untitled piece] / Brahms -- [Untitled piece] / Purcell -- Wecken -- Gavotte / Georg Muffat -- [Untitled piece] -- [Untitled piece] / Mozart -- Count me out -- A music quiz: Home on the Range, etc. / after Salieri -- Melchior vulpius -- [Untitled piece] -- Fugue für das Laufwerk: violins / Haydn / Jan. 1, 1946 -- Song of the syrens: sp. / Balthazarini (in Fiddle Sessions) -- Symphony / Tomkins -- [Untitled piece -- Untitled piece] -- "For 2 / ? or 4" -- Leopold (Ludwig?) Emperor of Austria" -- Who'll buy me roses -- [Untitled piece] -- Equali no. 2: orig. trombones / Beethoven -- From Thesaurus musicus / Handel -- Prayer / Franck.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Collection 1949: mostly material for special duet sessions 1949, 1 ms. sketchbook ([64] p.); 32 cm.; Arrangements for multiple types of ensembles. Title from prefatory page. "I find that most of this stuff has served multi-purpose, much of it used in print--largely in Sessions bks."--Note from Livingston Gearhart on inside cover. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 13, Folder 238)
    Contents: Dirty Work in the Dell -- Pavane -- Sicilienne -- Mazurka -- Scotch hop (based on Old Scotch melody) -- Bolero -- Scherzo -- Gavotte -- Habanera -- Hoppin' mad -- Reversible tune -- Rush-ya (or Rush hour in Russia) (based on Russian folk songs) -- Arabian revenge -- Habanera -- Tarantelle -- Minuet -- Lament -- Sinfonia -- Canon at one note's distance (Mendelssohn) -- Untitled (Beethoven) -- You name it -- Etude (Cherubini) -- Valsette (A. Mendelssohn) -- Dizzy spell -- Variations in styles on 5 master styles: -- Invention: [in the style of] J.S. Bach; Rondo from the "Revolutionary" Symphony "1773": [in the style of] J. Haydn; Epilogue, aus Sonate für zwei Dudelsack, Opus 176: [in the style of] J. Brahms; Stop yanking my heart (From Do-Do-Doodle again (1917)): [in the style of] George Gershwin; Jankj Dyde, Overture to Act III: [in the style of] Modeste Moussorgsky -- Duettino (C.P.E. Bach) -- Etude (L. Mozart) -- Little fugue on A B-A-D E-G-G - ("Egon Toast") -- Humoreske, or, Dvorâk turning over in his grave - ("Deranged") -- Maladay in F - with apologies to Tony Rubinstein and Dick Wagner -- Ping pong suite: I. Volley for Serve; II. Trick Shot; III. Exhibition Match; Reverse English (Backhand); Bonsoir mesdames or G'night, chicks -- Mixed metre (Mozart, adapted from Don Giovanni, Act II) -- Coronation minuet -- "Lady Nelson's" reel -- Jig (17th Century English) -- Prelude (Couperin) -- Gigue (Fanfare?) (Old English: 17th century) -- Trumpet tune (Purcell) -- Reverie (Schumann) -- New Cauliflower Cotillion -- Lest we forget... -- Gavotte (Georg Muffatt) -- Unidentified -- Carols -- Sicilienne (Folk: "Greensleeves," carol: "What child is this") -- Old English duets -- Air de trompettes -- Air grave de Mr. Tenoes (sp.?) -- Sonatas for two alto flutes / Gottfried Finger -- Unidentified -- Gavotte (?) -- Untitled -- Theme: Chopsticks; Var. I: The classic counter melody; Var. II: Chicken chatter; Var. II: Canon ("Chased"); Var. III: Chorale ("Chaste" or "Church"); Var. IV: Chimes; Var. V: Chronometer; Var. VI: Chromatics; Var. VII: Chicanery; Var. VIII: Ochi Chornya; Var. IX: Chopin!; Var. X: Chanson; Var. XI: Caroussel; Var. XII: Conclusion -- Tyrolean waltz (Ländler) -- In the cool cellar (Old German student song) -- Passacaglia (Duet for 2 Supermen).
  - Gearhart, Livingston Counterpoint exercises [1937], 8 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; Chiefly counterpoint exercises beginning in first species and concluding with fifth species. Title supplied by cataloger. "The handwriting of rules and corrections of the first 2 pp. is that of Nadia Boulanger. The remaining pages appear to be explorations of contrapuntal possibilities (observing THE RULES) by [Livingston Gearhart]"--Accompanying leaf from Livingston Gearhart. Holograph (Pencil). Text in English. (Box 13, Folder 239)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Counterpoint exercises with Boulanger corrections [between 1937 and 1940], 1 ms. sketchbook ([46] p.); 34 cm.; Chiefly species counterpoint exercises. Title from accompanying typescript note (1 leaf) from Livingston Gearhart. "Obviously, later, some pages were used for original (incomplete) sketches"--Accompanying typescript note. Holograph (Ink) (Pencil); Boulanger's corrections (Pencil). (Box 13, Folder 240)
  - Duet sessions: music for two in many combinations of [treble clef] instruments 1964, 1 score (64 p.); 31 cm.; Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 14, Folder 241)
    Contents: Air for viols / Francois Couperin -- Allegretto, from Symphony No. 1775 / Joseph Haydn -- Andante / John T. Crissey -- Andante and Rondo (K. 292) / W.A. Mozart -- Arabian reverie -- Arkansas traveller (Fiddle tune, U.S.) -- Bonaparte crossing the Rhine (Fiddle tune, U.S.) -- Bon soir, Mesdames / Livingston Gearhart -- Canon / J.S. Bach -- Chaconne (Old style) / Alte Schreiber -- Chinese lullaby -- Chopsticks chacony / Livingston Gearhart -- Cloud seven / Livingston Gearhart -- Close quarters / Livingston Gearhart -- Dizzy spell -- Duettino / C.P.E. Bach -- Duo / George P. Telemann -- Epilogue, from the incidental music for Jaencke der Dudelsackspieler / Johannes Brahms -- Etude / L. Cherubini -- Etude / Leopold Mozart -- Fandango / adapted from E. Chabrier -- Fanfare / Monteverdi -- Fanfare for a celebration / Manuel de Falla -- Fanfare pour Reveiller Le Bon Gros Roi des Singes / Erik Satie -- Folie a Deux -- Gavotte -- Habañera / Pierre Vivant -- Happy blues / Robert Hughes -- Improvisation over a theme of Cesar Franck / Livingston Gearhart -- Intervals: Suite and sour / Livingston Gearhart -- Jankj Dydl, Overture to Act VII, Scene xxvi (Modeste Moussorgsky) -- Jig / Livingston Gearhart -- Jungle jazz -- Kleptomania -- "Lady Nelson's" reel (British Isles) -- Lament / Kuhlau -- Malagueña / Livingston Gearhart -- Melody in F / Tony Rubinstein and Dick Wagner -- Minuet / W.A. Mozart -- Minuet, from the suite in C Minor for Flauto Traverso and Oboe d'amore / J.S. Bach -- Mixed metre for two -- Passacaglia / Raimondi -- Pavane / Pierre Vivant -- Phantasm / Prokofieff -- Ping Pong / Livingston Gearhart -- Real-nervous polka -- Reversible duet / Al Rovescio -- Rock! Rock your boat! (Deranged) -- Rushin' mood (based on Russian motifs) -- Scotch hop (based on a Scotch folk song) -- Scrambled airs -- Sicilienne / Livingston Gearhart -- Sicilienne (Greensleeves - English carol) -- Soliloquy / C. Debussy -- Stop yanking my heart, from Comes the revolution (1919) / George Gershwin -- Study in Fifths / Livingston Gearhart -- Suite Psycho-Pathetique -- Tarantelle -- Third degree larceny / Livingston Gearhart -- Toast to General Washington / Francis Hopkinson -- Tyrolean waltz -- Valse ignoble / Livingston Gearhart -- Variations on an American Air -- Variations on a theme by Paganini -- Waitin'-on-the-Northeast-Corner-of-166th-Street-and-6th-Avenue Blues / Livingston Gearhart.
  - Fiddle sessions 1947, 1 score (56 p.); 31 cm.; For 2-4 violins, unaccompanied. "For intermediate and advanced players." Includes index. New York: Shawnee Press (Box 14, Folder 242)
    Contents: After you, my dear Gaston: a canon in jazz for two / arranged -- Anticipation / Lassus -- Berceuse / Stravinsky -- Canon; Chorale / Bach -- Chorale / Wagner -- Close quarters / arranged -- The devil's dream / Old Amer. fiddle tune -- Double canon / Sweelinck -- Duet / Mozart -- Etude / L. Mozart -- Follow the leader: canon for three / Hayes -- Fugue / Haydn -- Gavotte / Muffat -- Hopak / Moussorgsky -- Lacrymosa: round for three / Schubert -- Lift thine eyes / Mendelssohn -- Madrigal / Purcell -- Meditation / Tschaikowsky -- Minuet / Haydn -- Minuet / Beethoven -- Mixed metre (for two); More mixed metre (for four) / arranged -- Pavane / Ravel -- Polka / Tschaikowsky -- PreluderP / Bach -- Rondo / Pleyel -- Round for three / Purcell -- Round for four / Brahms -- Round in 3 styles / arranged -- Theme / Mendelssohn -- Three rounds for three. Count me in / Caldara. Ariette / von Weber. Sky blue / arranged Prayer / Franck -- To the king's taste. Air for two viols / Couperin. Sarabande / Leopold I. Ballet / Baltazarini. Rigadoon / Quantz. Deep river / arranged -- Volga boatmen / arranged -- Zowie! Goes the weasel / Y. Dobon.
  - Flute sessions 1960, 1 score (63 p.); 32 cm.; "For intermediate to advanced players"--T.p. Original works and arrangements for 2, 3, or 4 flutes. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 14, Folder 243)
    Contents: Adagio / Kuhlau -- Air (from the St. Matthew Passion) / J.S. Bach -- Allegro / Quantz -- Badinerie / J.S. Bach -- Bolero (Canon) / LG -- A calisthenic canon / Klengel -- Canon (At one note) / Mendelssohn -- Canon (from "The musical offering") / J.S. Bach -- Canon over a ground bass (Alto flute) / Purcell -- Dialogues. Minorca; Improvisation over a theme of Cesar Franck; Simplicity; Dance / L. Gearhart -- Dirge (from "Ossian's Fingal") / Brahms -- Ditto; Dizzy spell / LG -- Duo / Anon. -- Esercizio sopra la scala / Palestrina -- Fluegel woogie (Round) / Devinez -- Gavotte / Georg Muffat -- Gavotte / LG -- The greenwood tree (Round) / Old English -- Hare & tortoise / Aesop -- Intermezzo / L. Gearhart -- Jungle jazz / LG -- Lament (Round) / Brahms -- Le coucou / Daquin -- Madrigal / Palestrina -- March / Handel -- Minuet / Beethoven -- Minuet / Haydn -- MinuetteuniM / Al Rovescio -- Misspelled music / Folk tune -- Pastorale / Igor Stravinsky -- Pavane / Maurice Ravel -- Phantasm / Prokofieff -- Prelude / J.S. Bach -- Rondo / Mozart -- Russian dance / LG -- Sarabande / Claude Debussy -- Scherzetto / J.T. Crissey -- Scherzo / K. Seitz -- Soliloquy / L. Gearhart -- The song of the lark (Piccolo and 2 flutes) / Tschaikowsky -- Sursum corda / Max Rairigh -- Swing! (Low, sweet...) / arranged LG -- Tarantelle (Canon) / LG -- Trio / Mozart -- Valse ignoble / LG -- Wintertime / Schumann.
  - Gentlemen songsters: two-, three-, and four-part songs for male voices (T.B., T.B.B., and T.T.B.B.) 1959, 1 score (96 p.); 27 cm.; Principally with piano accompaniment. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 14, Folder 244)
    Contents: Abalone -- Aura Lee -- Bunker Hill (1775) -- Choral bells -- A choral fanfare -- Cindy -- Contemplation -- Down in Arkansas -- Eternal Father, strong to save (Navy hymn) -- Ev'ry night when the sun goes in -- Four songs of the American revolution -- (I. The girl I left behind me; II. Bunker Hill; III. Toast to General Washington; IV. Yankee Doodle) -- The girl I left behind me -- Good news! -- Hand me down my walking cane -- Home on the range -- How silent is our village -- Hullabaloo belay! -- I've got no use for women -- Koom ba yah -- The lake -- Lo! How a rose e'er blooming -- Lord, I want to be a Christian -- Now the day is over -- O come, all ye faithful -- O come, poor folk and lowly -- O holy child -- Ol' Dan Tucker -- O worship the king -- The peanut song -- Pledge of Allegiance -- Set down, servant -- Slumber song -- A song of free men -- The Spanish guitar -- Toast to General Washington -- To music -- We gather together -- We wish you a Merry Xmas -- What shall we do with the drunken sailor? -- When Christ was born of Mary free -- When I was single -- Who threw the overalls in Mrs. Murphy's Chowder? -- Yankee Doodle.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Harmonic studies [between 1937 and 1940], 13 p. of ms. music; 34 cm.; Chiefly examples of harmonic progressions presented in textbook format with assignments. Topics covered include music fundamentals, 6/4 chords, the use of scale degree 7 in V7 chords, and realizing chords from figured bass. Livingston Gearhart presumably took these notes and used these exercises with Nadia Boulanger in Paris between 1937-1940. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink). Text in English. (Box 14, Folder 245)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Material for Clarinet sessions II [between 1976 and 1996], 1 box (19 folders).; Alternate title: Clarinet sessions II. Alternate title: Clarinet sessions 2. Material is for a proposed book which was never published. For various combinations of clarinets. Title from accompanying leaf. Most scores include clarinet parts. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 typescript leaf by Livingston Gearhart containing instrumentations for each piece. (Box 15, Folder 246-264)
    Contents: Minuet: for 2 clarinets and bass clarinet / Bach? -- Sinfonia IX: clarinet trio / J.S. Bach (abbreviated) -- The celebrated minuet (Antiques refinished) -- Andante religioso, op. 48 / G. Fauré -- A wotzit -- D minor string quartet / Mozart -- Etude / C. Rose -- Valse triste, op. 11 / Scriabin -- Tomkins -- Tune of celebration -- From La forza del destino / Verdi -- Antique minuet -- Canon -- Gavotte -- Mazurka -- Tarantelle -- [Untitled piece -- Untitled piece -- Untitled piece].
  - Gearhart, Livingston Musical composition sketchbook including Tango lament [1939], 1 ms. sketchbook ([24] p.); 20 x 26 cm.; Alternate title: Tango lamento. Includes incomplete Tango lament for wind quintet written in 1939 at Chatillon Coligny; also includes sketches, and exercises in counterpoint and score reading. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil and Ink). (Box 16, Folder 265)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Musical sketchbook [between 1940 and 1960?], 1 ms. sketchbook (77 p.); 32 cm.; Contains unfinished sketches, including a "Two piano ballet" and a prose outline for a murder mystery set as an opera. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 16, Folder 266)
  - Once upon a song: three and four part songs for treble voices, S.S.A and S.S.A.A. 1961, 1 score (96 p.); 27 cm.; Sacred and secular choruses with piano accompaniment and unaccompanied part songs. Delaware Water Gap, Pennsylvania: Shawnee Press (Box 16, Folder 267)
    Contents: Almost like being in love (Brigadoon) -- America, the beautiful (Unaccompanied) -- At the gate of heaven (Mexican folk lullaby) -- Ave Maria / Gabrieli (16th century) -- Beauty around us (Hymn) -- Bluebells (Rhythmic novelty) -- Bombo Lao (Congo Pygmy song) -- The camel (Humorous song) -- Cotton needs pickin' (Southern work song) -- Dirty dishes (Jazz round) -- Down on MacConnachy Square (Brigadoon) -- The eddystone light (American chanty) -- Ev'ry time I feel the spirit (Spiritual) -- Fiesta (South American dance) -- God of our fathers (Hymn) -- Guitar (Hebrew lament) -- The happy wanderer (Hiking song) -- The heather on the hill (Brigadoon) -- The holly and the ivy (Christmas) -- Holy, holy, holy (Hymn, unaccompanied) -- If I had an armadillo (Humorous song) -- Kissin's no sin (Scotch folk song) -- The Lord bless you and keep you (Benediction) / Lutkin -- Lully, lullay (Christmas) -- Night (Art song) / Duparc -- Not one single word (Sound advice) -- Oh, did'n' it rain! (Spiritual) -- Once upon a song (Theme song) -- O sin I so? (Musical curiosity) -- Pepper grinders (Greek folk dance) -- Rise to greet the sun (Chinese hymn) -- Scandalize my name (Southern folk song) -- Silent night (Christmas) -- Sinner, please don't let this harvest pass (Spiritual) -- Softly tread, the child is sleeping (Christmas) -- Songs from Brigadoon (Medley) -- Style stew (Novetly) -- Summer reverie (Art song) / Brahms -- Supplication (Canon) / Schubert -- 'Twas on the way to Bethlehem (Christmas) -- Turn back, o man (Song of brotherhood) -- Waterfall at Bac-Yon (Korean melody) -- We'll go a long, long way together (Gang song)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Quodlibets research [between 1940 and 1960?], 1 ms. sketchbook ([28] p.); 25 x 36 cm.; Contains comparisons of chordal structures used in various musical works, including folk songs, popular music, and classical repertoire. Title from prefatory page. Includes 3 leaves with ink line drawings: Sorcery, Nebula, and Vermin. Holograph (Pencil). Accompanied by 1 ms. sketch of Beautiful Ohio (Just a song at twilight) ([1] leaf); 1 ms. sketch of [The last rose of summer] ([1] leaf); 1 score (2 p.) of folk and popular songs. (Box 16, Folder 268)
  - Gearhart, Livingston Rhythm project materials [between 1976 and 1996], 2 boxes (97 folders).; Materials compiled for a proposed pedagogical book on rhythm. Title supplied by cataloger. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil). (Box 17-18, Folder 269-365)
    Contents: Box 1. Memos and written thoughts for the Rhythm project -- SR 1.05.A. Ostinato IV -- 1.9. Volley for serve -- 2.11. Suspensions, op. 11 / Scriabin; More of the same / de Vieux -- 2.12. A plague of rests; A sure thing -- 2.16. Something hidden -- 2.17. Plain and fancy -- 2.18. [Untitled piece]; Oriental ragtime; Close quarters; Hare and tortoise -- 2.2. Comparisons are advantageous -- 2.6. Not the way you remember it; Single-hurdle waltz / Romberg (?) -- 2.62. We gather -- 2.64. Waltz fragment / Brahms -- 2.65. The same, yet different -- 2.72. My ain kind dearie-o -- 2.73. The unconstant lover -- 2.83. Minimal melody / Offalbach -- 3.32. Haydn -- Before 3.4. From simplex to bothersome -- 3.6. Bottom of the ninth -- 3.71. For immediate cross-reference -- 3.81. Finnegan's wake -- 3.84. [Untitled piece] -- 3.85. Think 8 -- 4.1. Interval collisions / ½ Bach; Sequence -- 4.11. Air (Variation 1) / Purcell -- 4.15. The meaning of "subdivision" is this -- 4.4. [Untitled piece] -- 4.5. Jazz-related figures; The long wait; Ties from the litrachure -- 4.51. Sinfonia brevis -- 4.6. Fussy composers make reading more difficult -- 4.63. [Excerpt from Lieutenant Kije / Prokofiev] -- 4.64. Prokofieff -- 4.65. From [Symphony no.] 100 / Haydn -- 4.7. [Untitled piece] -- 4.71. Kastchei's infernal dance (Theme): [from The firebird / Stravinsky] -- 4.72. Air (Variation II) / Purcell -- 4.73. [Untitled piece] -- 4.8. Music of Athens (Georgia, that is); Motet / Giovanni Matteo Asola; Veni Emmanuel -- 5.51. Barbra Allen -- 5.54. Chaikovsky VI -- 5.8. Variations of gradually increasing agony; [Untitled piece] -- 5.9. Ragtime explained (Joplin); Ragtime rhythms (Debussy) -- 5.93. The entertainer (Joplin); Ragtime figures in [sixteenth notes] -- C5.94. Sync or sink -- Near 6.5. No connect -- 6.51. Chicanery -- 6.8. Sudden focus / Haydn -- Near 7.5. 2 v. 3: another approach -- 7.5. Rosetta stone 1 -- 7.B. The pattern -- 8.2. [Untitled piece] -- 8.3. [Trio] / Ravel -- 8.31. Bartok's "Bulgarian" rhythms -- 8.34. [Untitled piece] -- 8.6. Haydn -- 8.7. Gradual impoverishment; 2 fingers of wry; [Untitled piece] / Lassus -- 9.0. Grace notes; Antique minuet –
  - Rhythm sessions for strings: folder of manuscripts [between 1966 and 1996], 1 folder.; Holographs, chiefly in pencil: some accompanied by computer notated versions prepared by Fritz Gearhart for publication. Scored for string orchestra with optional third violin substitute part for the viola. The agony of rhythm XIX is based on My country 'tis of thee. (Box 19, Folder 366)
    Contents: Agony I [published as Rhythmic morphing] -- Agony VV: a canon, accompanied [published as Canon challenge in five] -- Rhythmic antics -- Valse incredeeble -- Noodle zoop agonies [published as Noodle zoop] -- Survival of the fittest -- Mississippi hot dog agony VXIII -- Pfui -- The agony of rhythm XIX: Terra cognita [published as Suite land of liberty] -- Sospirando: Agony IV -- Silver swan: Platinum pigeon [published as Madrigal madness] / [Orlando Gibbons] -- Cross rhythms -- Agony VX: Malagueña -- Scale stuff.
  - Rhythm sessions for strings 2004, 1 score (47 p.) + 6 parts; 28 cm.; Scored for string orchestra with optional third violin substitute part for the viola. Includes "rhythm glossary" in score (p. 44-46) and at the back of each part. Preface precedes score. Grafton, Ohio: Ludwig Music Publishing Co. (Box 19, Folder 367)
    Contents: Rhythmic morphing -- Canon challenge in five -- Rhythmic antics -- Valse incredeeble -- Noodle zoop -- Survival of the fittest -- Mississippi hot dog agony -- Pfui -- Suite land of liberty -- Sospirando -- Madrigal madness -- Cross rhythms -- Malagueña -- Scale stuff -- Rhythm glossary -- Appendix.
  - Gearhart, Livingston Sax sessions [between 1984 and 1988], 1 box (52 folders).; Materials are for Sax Sessions, a proposed addition to the Sessions series published by Shawnee Press which was never published. For various combinations of saxophones. "Livingston Gearhart 1996"--Copyright stamp on every page. Holograph (Pencil) (Box 20, Folder 368-419)